「當我們嘲笑魔鬼 告訴自己它不存在時…
那就是它最開心的時候
-加布裏爾阿莫斯神父
梵蒂岡首席驅魔師 1986-2016
1987年6月4日
特羅佩亞 - 意大利
好漂亮的豬
That's a beautiful pig.
一定是最好的 神父
Only the best, Father.
這邊請 神父
This way, Father.
這男孩表現出
The boy is showing
所有典型附身跡象 阿莫斯神父
all the classical signs of possession, Father Amorth.
家屬有沒有咨詢醫生？
Has the family consulted a doctor?
非常多的醫生
Many, many doctors.
是什麼樣的附身跡象？
What are the signs of possession?
他用英語交談 神父
He converses in English, Father.
他以前說過英語嗎？
Has he spoken English before?
沒有 從來都沒有
Never. Not once before.
他們有電視機嗎？
Do they own a television?
是的 應該有
Yes, I believe so.
好的 謝謝你
Okay, thank you.
你在畫什麼？
What are you drawing?
一隻鳥
A bird.
太棒了 孩子
That's good, kid.
我有個重要任務給你
I have a very important job for you.
你會念主禱文嗎？
Do you know the Our Father?
會 神父
- Yes, Father. - Good.
你可以幫你哥哥
You can help your brother.
不斷重複念主禱文
Repeat the Our Father, over and over.
不要分心 不停地念 明白嗎？
Don't get distracted. Relentless. Understood?
是 神父
Yes, Father.
好的
Good.
我們在天上的父 願人都尊你的名為聖…
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name...
把豬帶過來
Bring me the pig.
我是軍團
I am legion.
我是撒旦
I am Satan.
我是說骯話的龐然大物
I am foul-mouthed behemoth.
很難相信
Difficult to believe.
你懷疑我？
You doubt me?
如果你是撒旦 我叫什麼名字？
If you are Satan, what is my name?
形容地獄
Describe hell.
你很快會知道
You will find out soon enough.
你在逃避我的問題嗎？
Are you avoiding my questions?
你嘲笑我？
You mock me?
回答我 撒旦
Answer me, Satan.
為何附身在這男孩身上？
Why possess this boy?
為何不是更有影響力的人？
Why not someone more influential?
我可以附身…在我選擇的任何人身上
I can possess anyone I choose.
你能附身到吉安尼神父身上嗎？
Could you possess Father Gianni?
一個主教？
A bishop?
任何人 任何東西
Anyone! Anything!
我不相信
I do not believe you.
我不相信你連這隻豬都能附身
I don't believe you could even possess this pig.
你能嗎？你有能力
Can you do it? You have the power.
你能附身在這隻豬身上嗎？
Could you possess the pig?
-是 我能 -快 撒旦
- Yes, I can. - Come on, Satan.
-你看好  -附身在豬身上
Watch me! -Possess the pig.
讓我見識你就是黑暗王子
Show me you are the Prince of Darkness.
讓我見識你的能力
Show to me your power.
你附身了嗎？
Have you done it?
你附在它身上了 撒旦？
Have you possessed him, Satan?
Have you possessed it, Satan?
冷靜點
Be calm.
上帝保佑你
God blesses you.
現在你能睡了 孩子
You can sleep now, my son.
惡魔走了
The demon has gone.
上帝與你同在
God is with you.
教廷第一驅魔人
1987年7月1日
卡斯蒂利亞 - 西班牙
艾米 我們不在美國了 你不能那樣穿
Amy, we're not in America anymore. You can't dress like that.
為什麼？
Why?
因為到處都會有建築工人
Because there's gonna be construction workers everywhere.
你在後面還好嗎？
How you doing back there?
那麼…我們因為這個而拋棄一切？
So we left everything for this?
艾米 拜託 別開始
Amy, please. Don't start.
對啊 因為你就知道我打算說什麼
You know exactly what I'm gonna say.
是的 而且我不想聽
Yes, and I don't wanna hear it.
你覺得呢？還蠻酷的吧？
What do you think? Pretty cool, huh?
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
咕咕
Cuckoo!
加布裏爾
Gabriele.
你覺得聖邁克爾有機會時
Why do you think Saint Michael
卻沒有殺死撒旦是什麼原因？
didn't kill Satan when he had the chance?
那是一個神學的問題
That is a question of theology.
的確是
No shit.
也許正是他的憐憫留下了聖邁克爾的劍
Perhaps it was his mercy that stayed Saint Michael's sword.
阻擋上帝之愛的唯一東西…
The only thing that arrests God's love
就是一個人的自由意識
is a person's freedom to choose.
上帝連那可憎之物也給與自由…
But God cannot be God unless he allows for this choice
不然上帝就不是上帝了
even for the damned.
聖邁克爾 他知道這一點
Saint Michael, he knows this.
我們都將被審判
We will all be judged.
我們都將按照愛的程度…
We will all be judged
來面對審判
by how much we love.
別擔心 加布裏爾
Do not worry, Gabriele.
我會捍衛你的
I will defend you.
捍衛我？
Defend me?
我的信仰…
My faith
不需要捍衛
does not require defense.
哇
Wow.
大家覺得如何？-舒適
- What do you think, guys? - Cozy.
拜託 給它一個機會 這很棒
Oh, come on. Give it a chance. This is awesome.
卡洛斯 嗨
- Señora Vasquez. - Carlos, hi!
能和你見面還真好
So nice to put a face to the voice.
埃斯基貝爾神父…
Padre-- Father Esquibel...
很高興認識你 瓦斯克斯女士
Pleasure to meet you, Miss Vasquez.
就叫我茱莉亞
Uh, Julia, please.
-卡洛斯正帶我參觀 -太好了
- Carlos was giving me a tour. -  Oh, great.
我只想過來看看跟你和家人打個招呼
I just wanted to stop by and welcome you and your family
-歡迎你們來到教區 -抱歉
to the diocese. -  I'm sorry.
不 請 請繼續
Oh, no, no, no, please. Go for it.
你能平安來到真的太好了
I'm glad to see you made it safe.
好 去找你的房間 笨蛋
All right. Go find your room, twerp.
嗨 能給我一個嗎？
Hey. Can I get one of those?
當然
Yes, of course.
這房子年久失修
This property has been in disrepair
-從我記事起就這樣 -謝謝
- for as long as I can remember. - Thank you.
你正在做一件很棒的事 修復修道院
So it's a wonderful thing you're doing, restoring the abbey.
我們非常尊重現有的架構
We are being very respectful of the existing architecture.
它實際上已在我丈夫家中世代相傳
This has actually been in my husband's family for generations,
而我們剛剛繼承它
and we just inherited it.
瓦斯克斯先生在這還是…
Is Mr. Vasquez here or--?
其實他已經去世了 大約一年前
Oh, uh, he passed, actually. About a year ago.
我很遺憾 -沒關係
- I'm sorry for your loss. - It's okay.
如果有什麼需要 請說？不要猶豫
If you need anything, please, hm, don't hesitate.
好的
Okay.
我會為他祈禱
I will remember him in my prayers.
你太好了 謝謝 很高興認識你
Oh, that's very kind of you. Thank you. It was nice to meet you.
好 卡洛斯 跟我說 怎麼樣？我們在哪裏？
Okay, Carlos, talk to me. What's up? Where are we at?
要開挖地下室十分複雜
The basement excavation is very complicated.
-比你想的更貴…
More expensive, you mean?
-應該是 -好
-  I'm afraid so. -  All right.
我會再看一下圖
I'll take another look at the plans.
如果你能帶我去看看地下室
If you could just show me what the basement looks like,
也許我能接一些…
maybe I can wire--
艾米 在你摔斷脖子之前快下來
Amy, get off of there before you break your neck.
是煙嗎？請馬上把它滅了
Is that a cigarette? Put that out right now, please.
-好 -不 天啊
- Fine. - No! Oh, my God.
可愛
Cute.
滾出我的房間
Get out of my room.
你看到弟弟了嗎？
Hey, have you seen your brother?
艾米
Amy.
看…我真的受不了我兩個孩子的沉默對待
Look, I really can't handle the silent treatment from both my kids.
-我知道你不想來這裏 -確實是的
- I know you don't wanna be here. - Yeah, no shit.
艾米…
Amy.
拜託 我需要你的幫忙
Please, I need your help.
這修道院是你父親留給我們的唯一東西
This abbey is the only thing your dad left us.
我們已經沒有收入了
We don't have an income anymore.
我們把它修好後賣了就回家好嗎？
Once we fix it up and sell it, we'll go home. Okay?
也許你至少能幫我看好你弟弟
Maybe if you could just at least watch your brother.
也許嘗試讓他再次說話
Maybe try and get him to talk.
怎麼樣？他已經快一年沒說話了
How? He hasn't spoken in almost a year.
你能幫我試試看嗎？
Can you try for me?
你要我為了你做個媽媽？
So you want me to be a mother for you?
請幫忙看著你的弟弟 好嗎？
Please just keep an eye on your brother. Okay?
1987年7月2日
羅馬 - 意大利
拿著這個
Hold this.
阿莫斯神父
Father Amorth, caffe latte?
在這個時候？你瘋了？
At this time of the day? Are you crazy?
雙份濃縮咖啡 修女
Double espresso, Sister.
謝謝
Thank you.
糖？
Sugar?
糖是魔鬼的傑作 不要 謝謝
Sugar is the work of the devil. No, thank you.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
我們繼續吧
Let's get on with this already.
這是正式聽證會
This is a formal hearing.
按照約定 訴訟將以英語進行
And as agreed, proceedings will be undertaken in English.
好 開始吧
Ah. All right, let's go.
6月4日晚上 在特羅佩亞鎮
On the night of June 4th, in the town of Tropea,
你進行了驅魔
you performed an exorcism
未經雷焦卡拉布裏亞主教的批准
without the approval of the Reggio Calabria bishop.
用英語 阿莫斯神父
In English, Father Amorth.
那不是驅魔
That was not an exorcism.
根據吉安尼神父的描述 在雷焦卡拉布裏亞
From Father Gianni's description, what occurred in Reggio Calabria sounded
發生的事就是一場驅魔 而且還有動物祭祀
exactly like an exorcism, complete with animal sacrifice, no less.
那男孩心理失調 是一種暫時性精神疾病
The boy was maladjusted. A temporary mental illness.
我用了遠古心理學
I use primitive psychology.
暗示的力量
The power of suggestion.
把這個對象稱為撒旦 要求它展示它的能力
You addressed the subject as Satan, called for him to display his power.
- 你否認這一點嗎？-不
- Do you deny this? - No.
- 我就是這麼做的 -你為什麼要那樣做？
- That's what I did. - And why would you do that?
驅魔是我的職責
Exorcism is my job,
但我被分配到的絕大多數案件
but the vast majority of the cases to which I'm assigned
不需要驅魔
do not require an exorcism.
他們只需要一些交談
They just need, uh, a little conversation,
一點同理心
a little understanding,
有時…
and sometimes...
一些戲劇性
a little theater.
沙利文大主教 在我看來
Cardinal Sullivan, in my observation,
98% 分派給阿莫斯神父的案件…
98% of the cases that are assigned to Father Amorth
過後都被他進一步推薦給
are then further recommended by him
醫生和精神科醫生
to doctors and psychiatrists.
另外2%呢？
And the other 2%?
另外的2%
Ah, the other 2%.
這是長久以來 讓科學和醫學界
This is something that has confounded all of science
都感到困惑的事
and all of medicine for a very long time.
我稱之…
I call it...
邪惡
evil.
主教大人 成功驅魔數百次
Your Eminence, with hundreds of successful exorcisms,
-阿莫斯神父一直有效率地… -稍等 盧蒙巴主教
- Father Amorth has been very effective-- - One moment, Bishop Lumumba.
你確實提出了一個有意思的觀點 阿莫斯
You do raise an interesting point, Amorth.
你不是醫生 但你的這些做法
You are not a doctor, but these practices of yours
可能會對這些人造成破壞性影響
could have damaging effects on these people.
你說的沒錯
You are right.
我不是醫生
I am not a doctor.
我不是心理醫生
I am not a psychologist.
但我是神學家 律師
But I am a theologian, I am a lawyer,
記者 一個務實的人
I am a journalist, and I am a practical man.
我也是戰爭中的游擊隊 我懂得分辨行刑隊
I was also a partisan in the war, so I know a firing squad when I see one.
那麼 這是怎麼回事？
So, what is this about?
信理部已向
The Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith
委員會推薦
has recommended to this panel
取消首席驅魔師一職
that the position of chief exorcist be formally vacated.
所以 你的意思是邪惡不存在？
So, what you are saying is that evil does not exist?
教會一直面臨著提升其重要性的壓力
The Church is under constant pressure to sharpen her relevance.
是時候擺脫這些過時的信念了
It's time we move past these outdated beliefs.
請向我解釋一下 主教大人
Explain to me please, Your Eminence.
如果不存在邪惡
If evil does not exist,
那麼教會的作用是什麼？
what, then, is the role of the Church?
我認為我們都要小心信理部
I think we all have to be careful of the Congregation of the Doctrine of the Faith.
在我看來 他們希望我們都失業
Sounds to me like they want us all out of a job.
我們有更多問題要問你 阿莫斯神父
We have more questions for you, Father Amorth.
怎麼突然我就值得
How is it that I am suddenly worthy
你們這些有權勢的人花時間和精神了？
of the time and attention of all you powerful men?
我再問你…
I ask you again...
這是怎麼一回事？
what is this about?
正當程序 神父
Due process, Father.
所以 這與死去的女孩羅莎莉亞維倫德茲
So this is not about the dead girl, Rosaria Velendez,
我在 《上帝之母》雜誌上寫的無關？
that I write about in La Madre di Dio magazine?
您對此的盡職調查和流程是怎樣的？
What is your due diligence and process on this?
-拜託 大主教 -我警告你 阿莫斯神父
- Please, cardinal. - I warn you! I warn you! Father Amorth,
尊重你的上級
show respect to your superiors.
我有
I do!
我是梵蒂岡的首席驅魔師
I am the chief exorcist of the Vatican.
我的職位是由我的主教任命的
My position was appointed by my bishop.
我的教區是羅馬
My diocese is Rome.
我當地的主教是教皇
My local bishop is the pope.
如果你對我有問題
If you have a problem with me,
可以和我老闆談談 知道嗎？
you talk to my boss. Okay?
教皇的身體虛弱
The pope is infirm.
阿莫斯神父 你還不能離開
Father Amorth, you have not been dismissed.
-咕咕 -阿莫斯神父
- Cuckoo. - Father Amorth!
你好？
Hello?
有人在嗎？
Anyone there?
我想盡快完成這項工作
I can't wait to finish this job.
這地方讓我很害怕
This place freaks me out.
怎麼了？
What is it?
我不知道 什麼都看不到
I don't know. Can't see anything.
他們發現了一個天然氣礦床
They hit a gas deposit.
我們不能繼續在這工作 我會讓我的團隊撤退
We can't continue working here. I'm pulling my team from this place.
來吧 我們走吧 來吧 大家都出去
Come on, let's go. Come on, everybody out.
等等
Wait.
快 快
Quick, quick.
亨利？
Henry?
不 亨利
No. Henry!
媽媽
Mom!
天啊 亨利 發生什麼事？
Oh, my God! Henry! What is happening?
我不知道 我進來時他就這樣了
I don't know, he was like this when I came in.
亨利？亨利 是媽媽
Henry? Henry, it's Mommy.
跟我說話
Talk to me.
-亨利 -天啊 媽媽
- Henry. - Mommy.
他在說話
He's talking.
亨利 -媽媽…
- Henry. - Mommy.
你們都會死
You're all going to die.
亨利 你在做什麼？
Henry! What are you doing?
亨利 亨利
- Henry! Henry! -  Henry! Henry!
X光 驗血 連脊柱穿刺
X-rays, blood tests, even the spinal tap
和核磁共振成像 也未顯示缺血或血腫的結果
and MRI show no results of ischemia or hematoma.
什麼意思？
What does that mean?
他的所有生命體征和腦功能似乎都正常
All of his vitals and brain functions seem to be normal.
正常？什麼意思？他在抽搐
Wait, normal? What do you mean? He was convulsing.
他最近受過什麼創傷嗎？
Has he been through any trauma recently?
是 他爸爸在一年前過世了
Yeah, uh, his dad died about a year ago.
他的反應如何？
And how did he react?
從那以後他就沒說過話
He hasn't spoken since.
精神病？
Wha-- Psychosis?
不 不可能 他不過是個小孩
No, that's not possible. He's just a little boy.
太太 現在我們已無能為力了
Ma'am, there is nothing that we can do now.
-但他能推薦一位優秀的精神科醫生 -這是什麼？
- But he can recommend a good psychiatrist. -  What is this?
如果你兒子繼續試圖傷害自己
If your son continues trying to hurt himself,
-你可以給他這種鎮靜劑 -不
- you can administer him this sedative. - No.
-媽媽 -我很抱歉
- Mom. - I'm so sorry.
寶貝
Baby.
天啊
Oh, my God.
不 我覺得你不明白
No, I don't think you understand.
但這是緊急情況 拜託了
But this is an emergency, please.
不 我需要和領事館裏能幫我的人談談
No, I need to talk to someone at the consulate who can help me.
我需要一個專家
I need a specialist.
好
Okay.
是的 拜託
Yes, please.
寶貝
Baby.
嘿
Hey.
我的愛 過來
My love, come here.
去死吧
Fuck this.
亨利 不要
- Henry, no. -
亨利 停
Henry, stop!
你的寶貝餓了 你這肥牛
This baby's hungry, you fat cow.
什麼？你說什麼？
What? What are you saying?
你從來都沒有以母乳餵過我 媽媽
You never breastfed me, Mommy.
-什麼？ -搞什麼？
- What? -  What the fuck?
恨
那是什麼？
What the fuck is that?
把牧師給我帶來
Bring me the priest.
-你能幫我們嗎？ -是的
-  Can you help us? -  Yes.
我是來幫忙的 茱莉亞
I'm here to help, Julia.
好
Okay.
不是這個牧師
Wrong fucking priest!
是你嗎 加布裏爾？-是的 教皇
- Is that you, Gabriele? -  Yes, Holy Father.
他們告訴我你病了
They tell me you are sick.
對 他們希望如此
Yes, they hope so.
他們希望看到我虛弱
They wish to see me weak.
但我不是
But, no, they are.
幫幫我
- Help me. - Yes.
也許我們太盡責了
Perhaps we've done our jobs too well.
蘇利文大主教和年輕一代
Cardinal Sullivan and the younger generation,
他們不相信我們所理解的魔鬼
they don't believe in the devil as we understand it.
對他們來說那只是概念 對我們來說是真實的
It's only an idea for them. For us, it is very real.
200個墮落的天使
Two hundred fallen angels,
被逐出天堂 被驅趕到土地之下
expelled from heaven, driven beneath the soil where God is not welcomed.
那不是童話
It is not a fairytale.
你對真理的探索是令人欽佩的 加布裏爾…
Your search for truth is delightful, Gabriele,
但要注意你的教育意願
but pay attention to your desire to educate.
驕傲有不同的表現形式
Pride manifests itself in different forms.
驕傲？我？
Pride? Me?
有一個案例需要你的關注
There's a case that needs your attention.
一個在西班牙的男孩
A boy in Spain.
這件事讓我很不安
Something about it disturbs me greatly.
這孩子的附身進展得非常快
This boy's possession is progressing very fast.
事發地點在聖地
The incident took place in hallowed ground,
卡斯蒂利亞的聖塞巴斯蒂安修道院
San Sebastian Abbey in Castile.
這個地方以前給教會帶來了問題
This place has given the Church problems before.
我感覺到一股巨大的邪氣從那裏傳來
I sense a great evil coming from there.
只有你能幫助解決的黑暗力量
Something dark that only you can help solve.
我已要求將修道院的記錄帶到圖書館給你
I have requested the abbey's records be brought to you in the library.
調查一下
Look into it.
我會在你前去途中繼續調查
I will continue investigating while you're on your journey.
你們的罪必追上你們
「你們的罪…
"Our sins...
必追上你們 」
will seek us out."
加布裏爾
Gabriele.
去西班牙幫助這個孩子
Go to Spain, and help this child.
但要小心 聽起來這個惡魔很危險
But be careful, this demon sounds dangerous.
你好？
Hello?
神父
Father.
早上好 我是托馬斯·埃斯奎貝爾神父
Good morning. I'm Father Tomas Esquibel.
-西班牙語？-對
- Spanish? - Yes.
我是阿莫斯神父 意大利人
I am Father Amorth. Italian.
等等 阿莫斯神父？
Wait. Father Amorth? - Yes.
沒想到他們會派你來
I didn't expect them to send you.
你認識我？
You know me?
是的 我讀過所有的文章
- Yes. I have read all the articles. -
-還有書本？ -不 書還沒有
- And the books? - No, no. No, not the books.
那些書都不錯
The books are good.
我會看的… -好 我去拿行李
- I will read-- - Okay. I'll just get my bag.
你…威士忌？
You, uh...  Whiskey?
不 謝謝
No, no, no. Thank you.
對 這喉嚨痛 還有…灰塵
Yeah, this sore throat, the dust.
茱莉亞 我們很幸運 教會派人來了
Julia, we have been extremely lucky. The Church sent someone.
是這方面的專家 加布裏爾 請進
An expert in these matters. Gabriele, please come in.
早上好
Good morning, good morning, good morning.
我是阿莫斯神父
I am Father Amorth.
我來自羅馬
I have come from Roma.
加布裏爾…
Gabriele, how are you?
很抱歉讓你千里迢迢過來…
I'm sorry that you came all this way,
但我不知道教會為何在關注這件事
but I don't even know why the Church is interested in this.
我只希望我兒子能好起來
I just want my son to be well.
會沒事的
Yes, yes.
告訴我…有醫生給你答案或安慰了嗎？
Tell me something, have the doctors given you any answers?
有什麼安慰嗎？
Any comfort?
請你至少讓我…
If you would at least...
看看你兒子
just let me see your son.
我可以給你意見 然後隨便你怎麼做
I can give you my opinion and you can do with it what you will.
值得一試
It's worth a shot.
好 他在樓上
Okay. He's upstairs.
很好 這個
Very nice, this.
你好 我的朋友
Hello, my friend.
亨利…
Henry.
你醒著嗎？
Are you awake?
你的禱告在這裏是沒用的
Your prayers are worthless here.
你是誰？
Who are you?
你最害怕的事 我是你的終結者
Your worst fear. I am your demise.
你為何要附身這孩子？
Why are you possessing this boy?
因為毀掉如此無辜的肉體感覺真好
Because it feels so good to ruin such innocent flesh.
但我更喜歡挑戰驅魔師的靈魂
But I prefer the challenge of an exorcist's soul.
你只會讓你自己終結
You only serve to diminish yourself.
不要教訓我 牧師
Don't lecture me, priest.
你有什麼目的？
What is your purpose?
我是來找你的
I'm here for you.
那你一定知道我的名字
Then you must know my name.
我知道你的靈魂 以及每一個無恥的罪
I know your soul and every shameless sin.
你說說我的一個罪過
Tell me one of my sins.
你說不出
You cannot.
因為我的罪已被真正的主
Because my sins have been absolved by the one true master,
- 主耶穌基督赦免了 -別提祂了
- the Lord Jesus Christ. - Do not speak of him.
你怕祂？你害怕耶穌基督嗎？
Are you afraid of him? Are you afraid of Jesus Christ?
上帝不在這裏
God is not here.
上帝是無所不在的
God is everywhere.
無論你做什麼…
Whatever you do...
是因為上帝允許才能做到
you only do because God allows it.
祂允許那樣嗎？
Did he allow that?
這只是開始
This is just the beginning.
你不知道你在和誰打交道
You don't know who you're dealing with.
那就告訴我 告訴我你的名字
Then tell me. Tell me your name.
除非你太害怕
Unless you are too afraid.
我不是那些會被你說服而附身在豬的蠢貨
I'm not some stupid fuck you convince to get into a pig.
那麼你不肯告訴我你的名字
So you won't tell me your name.
我叫褻瀆神明
My name is blasphemy.
我叫噩夢
My name is nightmare.
我的噩夢…
My nightmare...
是法國贏得世界盃
is France winning the World Cup.
你這個驕傲的傻瓜
You prideful fool.
你不能永遠躲在你的笑話後面…
You can't hide behind your jokes forever...
加布裏爾
Gabriele.
我也知道你的噩夢
I know your nightmares too.
出來吧 膽小鬼
Show yourself, coward.
出來吧
Show yourself.
懦夫
Coward.
出來 懦夫
Show yourself, coward.
當心 你的罪必追上你們
Beware, your sins will seek you out.
我會等你的 加布
I'll be waiting for you, Gabe.
你有沒有向這屋裏的任何人提過我的名字？
Did you mention my name to anyone in this house?
可能有 我不肯定
Maybe, I'm not sure.
這惡魔… 它說了它不該知道的東西
This demon, it says things that it could not know.
那麼 它是真的？
So it's real?
你對惡魔的瞭解有多少？
What do you know about demons?
只有基礎知識 他們是墮落的天使
Only the basics, that they are fallen angels.
以著等級制度 一個服侍著另一個
One serves the other in a hierarchy.
等級越高的惡魔 它能侵入的管道越多
The higher the demon, the more access it can have.
它為何要附身那個男孩？
So why is it possessing the boy?
這是個好問題 我會和他母親談談
This is a very good question. I'm going to talk to the mother.
我要弄清楚這惡魔為什麼選擇亨利
I need to work out why this demon has chosen Henry.
我接下來要說的話… 也許很難接受 正視它
What I am about to say may be difficult. Confronting.
你的兒子被一個非常強大的惡魔附身
Your son is under the influence of a very powerful demon.
帶走這孩子可能會致命
Removing the boy from this place could be fatal.
現在我跟你說…
I say to you now...
你兒子回到你身邊的唯一方法 就是藉著信仰
the only way your son comes back to you is through faith.
瓦斯克斯太太 亨利之前是否出了什麼事？
Mrs. Vasquez, did anything happen to Henry?
他遭遇了殺死他父親的車禍
He was in the car accident that killed his father.
他看到他父親被刺穿
He saw his father impaled.
那段記憶… 那就是他的惡魔
That memory, that's his demon.
我答應你
I give you my word,
我不會離棄你或你兒子
I will not walk away from you, or your son.
正如你所說 那種創傷可能是魔鬼附身的途徑
Trauma such as you describe can be a gateway for the devil.
苦難會讓一個靈魂渴望聯繫
Suffering can make a soul desperate for connection.
它會使無辜者更加脆弱
It can make the innocent more vulnerable.
你之前一定十分愛你的丈夫
You must have loved your husband very much.
非常愛
You have no idea.
他曾是你的靈魂聯繫
He was your soul connection, si?
他就是一切
He was everything.
而且你有兩個漂亮的孩子
And you have two beautiful children.
媽媽的愛… 是最接近上帝之愛的東西
A mother's love is the closest thing we know to God's love.
告訴我 茱莉亞…
Tell me, Julia.
你曾相信過嗎？
Have you ever believed?
我小時候…
Uh, when I was a little girl...
曾經以為我的守護天使陪我上學
I used to think that my guardian angel walked me to school.
你應該向那個守護天使禱告
You should pray to that guardian angel.
亨利？
Henry?
艾米
Amy.
我在地獄
I'm in hell.
艾米 親愛的 是爸爸 你一定要聽 好嗎？
Amy, honey, it's Dad. You have to listen, okay?
爸爸？
Daddy?
你們都會死
You're all going to die.
媽 媽
Mom! Mom!
媽 是爸爸 是爸爸
Mom, it was Daddy. It was Dad.
我聽見爸爸的聲音 我在電話裏聽見他的聲音
I heard Dad's voice. I heard his voice on the phone.
-他說我們都會死 -什麼？
- He said that we're all gonna die. - What?
-他說我們都會死 -天啊
- He said that we were all gonna die. - Oh, my God.
我們該怎麼辦？
What do we do?
咖啡
Coffee.
那些惡魔在夜晚會更強大
The demons, they grow more strongly in the night.
我需要能量 但你應該盡量休息一下
I'm going to need my energy. But you should try to get some rest.
願所有逝去的信徒的靈魂
And may the souls of all the faithful departed,
在上帝的憐憫下 安息
through the mercy of God, rest in peace.
- 阿門 -這需要多久？
- Amen. -  How long will this take?
那很難說
That is hard to say.
幾個小時
Hours.
也許幾天
Days, maybe.
這惡魔很強
This demon is very strong.
這孩子撐不了多久
The boy won't last long.
我們該做的事…就是找出它的名字才能驅魔
What we need to do is to find out its name in order to exorcize it.
那就是我們能拯救那孩子的唯一方法
That is the only way we can save the boy.
我們該怎麼做？
How do we do that?
以著禱告
With prayer.
不斷的祈禱
Constant prayer.
惡魔… 它們是自保的
The demons, they are self-preserving.
他們不瞭解痛苦
They do not understand suffering.
最終 它會投降
Eventually, he will give himself up
因為它無法忍受禱告的痛
because he cannot stand the pain of the prayer.
你明白嗎？
You understand me?
-是的 -很好
- Yes. - Good. Good.
-現在你必須懺悔你的罪過 -現在？
- Now, you must confess your sins. - Now?
如果沒有被赦免 惡魔能聞到你的罪孽
The demon can smell your sins if they are not absolved.
來
Come.
我們開始
We begin.
原諒我 神父…
Forgive me, Father...
因為我犯了罪
for I have sinned.
自從…
It has been, uh...
-我上次告白已八個月… -神父 不
- eight months since my last confession-- - Padre, no.
你剛才說你距離上次告白已八個月了嗎？
Did you just say eight months since your last confession?
是的 -我…
- Yes. - I...
好 我們一定要做好這件事
Okay, we just have to get this done.
你是神的僕人 夠簡單的
- You are a man of God, simple enough, si? - Yes.
你為你所有的罪過感到非常抱歉
And you are very, very sorry for all of your sins.
-是的 -好
- Yes. - Okay.
願全能的神憐憫你…
May almighty God have mercy on you,
並且赦免了你的罪…
and having forgiven your sins,
帶領你走向永恆的和平  阿門
lead you to eternal peace. Amen.
你知道哪些驅魔儀式？
What rites of the exorcism do you know?
-沒有 -沒有？
- None. - None?
從來沒談論過
It has never come up.
哪些禱告是你即使在壓力下也能持續地做的？
What prayer do you know that you could say over and over, even under pressure?
聖母經
The Hail Mary.
但如果在壓力之下 我比較喜歡用西班牙語說
But if it is under pressure, I would prefer to say it in Spanish.
沒問題
That's fine.
你的任務…就是禱告
Your job is to pray.
不要與惡魔接觸
Do not engage with the demon.
不要回應它所說或所做的事
Do not respond to anything it says or does.
你的任務是堅持不懈
Your job is to be implacabile.
堅持不懈 知道嗎？
Relentless. Okay?
乖孩子
Good boy.
- 你會說笑話嗎？-不
- You know any jokes? - Eh... no.
你應該學一些 魔鬼不喜歡笑話
You should learn some. The devil does not like jokes.
把書帶上
Bring the books.
天堂的氣味
The scent of heaven.
看來你把朋友帶來了
I see you've brought your friend.
他看來有點害怕 加布
He looks a little scared, Gabe.
介意我叫你加布嗎 加布？
Mind if I call you Gabe, Gabe?
準備好戰鬥了嗎？
Readying for battle?
上次你逃走了
You ran out on me last time,
你就像個懦夫 小士兵
like the coward you are, soldier boy.
不太適合成為首席驅魔師
Not very becoming of the chief exorcist.
今天你打算被誰征服 耶穌還是祂媽媽？
Who do you want to be vanquished by today, Jesus or his mother?
混蛋的聖母
Fuck the Holy Mother.
我們是要談一整夜還是你想戰鬥？
Are we going to talk all night, or do you want to battle?
知道我要對你做什麼嗎 加布裏爾？
Know what I'm going to do to you, Gabriele?
我會睡了你
I'm going to fuck you.
你會感覺到高潮
You'll sense yourself coming.
然後你會因為我睡你時的釋放… 而恨自己
And you'll hate yourself for the release you feel when I fuck you.
現在我們祈禱
And now we pray.
我命令你 污鬼 無論你是誰
I command you, unclean spirit, whoever you are,
以及現在你所有攻擊著上帝的僕人 亨利的爪牙
along with all of your minions now attacking the servant of God, Henry,
藉著道成肉身的奧秘
by the mysteries of the incarnation...
-去你的的化身 -受難 復活
- Fuck you and your incarnations. - ...passion, resurrection
和我們主耶穌基督的升天 藉著聖靈的降臨
and ascension of our Lord Jesus Christ, by the descent of the Holy Spirit,
藉著我們主的降臨施行審判
by the coming of our Lord for judgment,
你用某種跡象告訴我…
to tell me by some sign
你的名以及你離開的日期和時間
your name and the day and hour of your departure.
托馬斯 祈禱
Tomas, pray. Pray.
此外 我命令你 確實服從我
I command you, moreover, to obey me to the letter,
儘管我不配 但我是上帝的牧師…
I who am a minister of God, despite my unworthiness--
羅莎莉亞？
Rosaria?
你們的罪必追上你們
Your sins will seek you out.
我的罪已經被赦免了
My sins have been forgiven.
但你不能原諒自己 不是嗎 神父？
But you can't forgive yourself, can you, Father?
不是為了我… 那個你任由她死去的女孩
Not for me, the girl you let die.
你為什麼什麼都不做？
Why did you do nothing?
你為什麼不相信我？
Why didn't you believe me?
現在 我在地獄了
Now I am in hell.
騙子
Deceiver.
她的靈魂安息了
Her soul rests in peace.
我的靈魂在地獄裏腐爛著
My soul rots in hell!
真感人
How touching.
你只有這些嗎？
Is that all you got?
那你呢 嗅內褲的？
And how about you, panty sniffer?
你沒告訴他吧？
You didn't tell him, did you?
關於你的小妓女？
About your little whore?
你的小甜心 阿黛拉
Your little sweet treat, Adella.
你站在你的會眾面前 就像你比他們更好
After you stood before your congregation like you're better than them,
同時又在上他們的女兒
when you're fucking their daughters.
也許你對那個罪並沒有那麼難過？
Maybe you aren't so sorry about that sin.
閉嘴
Shut up.
托馬斯 不要和它說話
Tomas. Tomas. Do not speak to it.
-祈禱 -快逃
- Pray. - Run away.
你不想待在這裏 托馬斯
You don't want to be here, Tomas.
你寧願和那個小婊子上床
You'd rather be fucking that little whore.
托馬斯 不要 不 那就是它的目的
Tomas! Tomas! No! No, no! That's what it wants!
你被耍了 阿莫斯
You've been played, Amorth.
你上當了
You took the bait.
而且我會毀了你
And I'll destroy you.
你的神聖教會將從內部崩潰
Your holy Church will crumble from the inside.
修道院的記錄 教皇
The abbey's records, Your Holiness.
她是我一生的摯愛
She was the love of my life.
我做出了承諾
A promise was made.
她要我…
She wanted me to...
為了她放下聖職
leave the priesthood for her...
但我…
but I had...
無意那樣做
no intention of doing that.
所以我就告訴她她想聽的東西
So I just told her what she wanted.
我對上帝的愛…
My love for God...
超過了我對她的愛
it outweighed my love for her.
你為自己的罪過感到難過嗎？
Are you sorry for your sins?
是的
Yes.
願全能的上帝憐憫你
May almighty God show you mercy.
並且赦免了你的罪過
And having forgiven your sins,
願祂帶領你進入永生
may he lead you to eternal life.
阿門
Amen.
誰是…
Who is...
羅莎莉亞？
Rosaria?
她是一個我本該幫助的女孩
She is a girl that I should've helped.
惡魔利用她的記憶來欺騙我
The demon is using her memory to deceive me.
它是怎麼知道這些事？
How does it know these things?
它能感覺到我們的罪惡感
It can sense our guilt,
並利用它來對付我們 讓我們分心
and it uses it against us as a distraction.
那個男孩 他就快死了
That boy, he does not have long before he expires.
我們必須找出這惡魔的名字
We need to find out the name of this demon.
找出它的名字會使他們變弱
Knowing its name, it weakens them.
我不是有意傷害他的
I didn't mean to hurt him.
我明白
I understand.
看這裏
See here.
我已經替你標記這一頁
I have marked this page for you.
去學它
Learn that.
但它是拉丁文
But it is in Latin.
蠻像西班牙語的
Close enough to Spanish.
用拉丁語祈禱更有力量
Prayer has more power in Latin.
「你上當了 」
"You have taken the bait."
-什麼？ -它對我說的話
- What? - What it said to me.
「你上當了 阿莫斯 」
"You have taken the bait, Amorth."
這和那孩子無關
This is not about the boy.
它有更大的計劃
It has a bigger plan.
我需要檢查一些我在花園裏看到的東西
I need to check something I saw in the garden.
去 拿著這個 站在他門外 他還沒脫離危險
Go. Take this. Be outside his door. He is still in danger.
我們一定要盡全力保護他 做你該做的事
We must protect him at all cost. Do whatever you have to.
梵蒂岡的印章
The seal of the Vatican.
這地方以前給教會帶來了問題
This place has given the Church problems before.
上帝 奉禰的名…拯救我
God, by your name... save me.
幫助我
Help me.
亨利？
Henry?
沒有人能活著離開這裏
No one's getting out of here alive!
沒有人
No one.
看看你隱藏了什麼秘密
Let's see what secrets you are hiding.
發生什麼事？
What happened?
去
Go!
救我
Help me!
阿莫斯
Amorth!
救我
Help me!
救命
Help!
艾米
Amy!
以主的名義 讓她走吧
In the name of Christ, let her go.
艾米
Amy!
救命
Help!
以主的名義 讓她走吧
In the name of Christ, let her go.
是我
It's me. It's me.
天啊 艾米
Oh, my God. Oh, Amy.
以主的名義 走開 撒旦 走開
In the name of Christ, go away, Satan, go away!
是她的一個指甲
It's one of her nails.
托馬斯 帶他們去教堂
Tomas, take them to the chapel.
一切已被節錄
Everything is redacted.
"你們的罪必追上你們"
"Our sins will seek us out."
「你們的罪必追上你們 」
-你還好嗎？ -是的
- Are you okay? - Yes.
這個行業無法允許你保持帥氣太久
You don't get to stay handsome in this business for too long.
拜託 不要
Please. Hm? Don't.
曾經有個惡魔試圖把一個十字架放入我的眼球
I once have a demon try to put a crucifix into my eyeball.
你總是一直說 夠了
You're always talking and talking. Enough.
求求你
Please.
他們在睡覺
They're sleeping.
別再說什麼故事了
No more stories.
你是否想過惡魔為何要這樣？
Did you consider why the demon does this?
讓我們害怕？
To scare us, hm?
為了什麼？
For what benefit?
混亂
Chaos.
分心
Distraction.
魔鬼是大騙子
The devil is the great deceiver.
他能讓你看到過去的事
He can make you see things from your past.
幻象 回憶 總是試圖欺騙我們
Apparitions, memories, always trying to deceive us.
那樣我們永遠不知道它在想什麼 計劃什麼
So we never know what he's thinking, what he's planning.
如果你不相信我…
If you do not believe me...
問我朋友吧
just ask my friend.
來 我帶你去看我的發現
Come, I'll show you what I found.
阿莫斯
Amorth!
我剛到的時候注意到了這一點
I noticed this when I first arrived.
這是什麼？
What is this?
你認得這個嗎？
You recognize this?
是的 是西班牙宗教裁判所的標誌
Yes, it's the seal of the Spanish Inquisition.
基督徒史上最黑暗的時期
Si. The darkest time in the history of the Church.
而他們是…
And they are...?
受害者 那些不皈依的人
The victims. The ones who would not convert.
這個地方下面有東西
There is something underneath this place.
這裏隱藏著一些東西  來
Something is hidden here. Come.
拿著
Hold this.
兩個交叉的鑰匙
Two crossed keys.
你認得這個嗎？
Do you recognize this?
這是梵蒂岡印章
- It's the Vatican seal. -
-是氣體嗎？- 一點
- Is it gas? -  A little gas.
少許硫磺 一點死亡
A little sulfur. A little death.
那麼 不可抽煙？退後
So no smoking, huh?  Stand back.
是一個門 跟我一起推
It's a door. Push with me.
好
Okay.
地下墓穴
Catacomb.
這就是他們埋葬死者的方式
This is how they would bury the dead.
我知道梵蒂岡封鎖了這個地方
I understand the Vatican sealing this place off.
但是他們為什麼要留下一個人呢？
But why would they leave someone?
大主教保護者的戒指
The ring of the cardinal protector.
他是最後的希望 最後的保護者
He was the final hope, the last protector.
看起來他是個囚犯 但他不是
It looks like he's a prisoner, but he's not.
籠子是為了他自己的安全
The cage is for his own safety.
他們這樣做…
They do this when an exorcism fails.
就是驅魔失敗的時候 為了防止惡魔逃脫
To protect against a demon's escape,
困住他們需要隱藏的東西
to trap something they need to remain hidden.
托馬斯 看看你能不能打開這扇門
Tomas, see if you can open this gate.
你的大主教保護者寫信通知你 我們最擔心的事
"Your cardinal protector writes to inform you of our worst fears.
一個強大的邪惡已佔據了聖塞巴斯蒂安修道院
A great evil has taken hold of San Sebastian Abbey.
它必須永遠被埋葬在這裏
It must be buried here forever."
鎖上了
It's locked.
那我們這個朋友…
Then our friend here...
一定有鑰匙
must have a key.
你把鑰匙藏在那裏了？
Where did you hide your key?
在肚子裏
In the stomach.
原諒我
Forgive me.
試這個
Try this.
去
Go.
所有的驅魔行動都失敗了
"All attempts at exorcism have failed.
現在這地方是屬撒旦的
Satan owns this ground now.
我從來沒見過 如此強大的惡魔
I have never seen a demon this powerful before."
加布裏爾
Gabriele.
成功了
It worked.
謝謝你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
艾米？
Amy?
那些氣體和硫磺 越來越強了
The gases and the sulfur, it's getting stronger.
我們離地獄越來越近了
We are getting closer to hell.
沙利文大主教 他還好嗎？
Cardinal Sullivan, is he all right?
他昏倒了
He collapsed.
教皇
Holy Father.
你只是情緒激動
You are just agitated.
告訴他
Tell him.
告訴誰？
Tell who?
加布裏爾
Gabriele.
加布裏爾？
Gabriele?
阿莫斯？
Amorth?
這一次他又害我們惹什麼麻煩了？
What trouble has he got us into this time?
德奧哈達修士
The Friar De Ojada.
有史以來最偉大的驅魔人之一
One of the greatest exorcists of all time.
西班牙宗教裁判所的標誌
The seal of the Spanish Inquisition.
他的日記
His journal.
「今天 我被召喚到塞哥維亞小鎮 」
"Today...I was summoned to the town of Segovia."
一個被附身的僧人
A possessed monk.
「在我們主的那年 1475年…
"In the year of our Lord 1475.
在審問附身僧人的惡魔時
While questioning the demon possessing the monk,
他從另一個人的口中回答我
he answered me from the mouth of another.
然後是第三個 」
And then a third."
附身多人 是個強大的惡魔
Multiple possessions. It's a powerful demon.
艾米？
Amy?
「驅魔人著了魔 」
"The exorcist becomes possessed himself."
德奧哈達修士？
Friar De Ojada?
他是說服伊莎貝拉女王…
You know he is the man who convinced Queen Isabella
成立宗教裁判所之必要性的人
of the need for an Inquisition?
所以這意味著他在1475年被附身
So that means from the time he is possessed in 1475,
這之後發生的一切…
everything that happens after this...
是魔鬼的傑作
is the work of the devil.
幾個世紀的迫害和折磨
Centuries of persecution and torture,
宗教裁判所最嚴重的濫用職權
the worst abuses of the Inquisition,
一切由修士以上帝的名義開始…
all started by the friar and done in the name of God
都是魔鬼做的
by the devil.
梵蒂岡一定知道這一點
The Vatican must have known this.
教會掩蓋了這事
The Church covered it up.
並把真相埋在這裏
And they buried the truth here.
「你們的罪必追上你們 」
"Your sins will seek you out."
一定是建築工程釋放了惡魔
The construction work must have freed the demon.
艾米？
Amy?
亨利
Henry.
沒事 媽媽
- It's okay, Mommy. - It's okay, Mommy.
亨利沒事了
- Henry's okay. - Henry's okay.
太好了
that's great.
聽好 艾米 不然你跟我到樓下去吧？
Listen, Amy, why don't you come downstairs with me?
抱歉 媽媽
- I'm sorry, Mom. - I'm sorry, Mom.
我不知道我被什麼附身了
- I don't know what got into me. - I don't know what got into me.
沒關係
Well, that's okay.
沒關係 我只是…我只需要你姐姐一會兒 艾米…
That's okay. I just need your sister for a minute. Amy?
你能原諒我嗎 媽媽？
- Can you forgive me, Mom? - Can you forgive me, Mom?
「大龍被摔在地上
"The great dragon was hurled down.
被驅逐到地上 把它捆綁在地 」
Hurled into the earth, where he was bound."
「它的使者跟著它 」啟示錄
"And his angels with him." Revelations.
兩百個狂暴天使埋入地上
Two hundred rogue angels buried into the earth.
這個修道院是那些被神遺忘的地方之一
This abbey is one of those godforsaken places.
這惡魔 它試圖找出它們
This demon, he was trying to find them.
以募集軍隊並摧毀教會
To raise an army and destroy the Church.
艾米 過來
Amy, come here.
你手上拿著什麼 媽媽？
- What's in your hand, Mommy? - What's in your hand, Mommy?
艾米 過來 馬上
Amy, come here, right now.
你手上拿著什麼 媽媽？
- What's in your hand, Mommy? - What's in your hand, Mommy?
看
Look.
看我 媽媽
Watch me, Mommy.
看我
Watch me.
它的名字…
His name...
地獄之王
the king of hell...
阿斯蒙蒂斯
Asmodeus.
快
Quickly!
艾米 用鎮定劑
Amy, use the sedative.
把他的手綁起來
Tie his arms.
我們知道它的名字了
We have his name.
「把牧師帶來 」
"Bring me the priest."
你剛剛說什麼？
What did you say?
這是惡魔說的第一句話 "把牧師帶來"
Those were the first words the demon said. "Bring me the priest."
它說的不是我
It didn't mean me.
它要的是你
It wants you.
這個惡魔以附身驅魔人為生
This demon feeds on exorcists.
它曾經有過一個計劃
He had a plan once.
把修士引誘到這裏…
To lure the friar here,
隱藏在正義中 以上帝的名做出令人髮指的事
hide amongst the righteous and commit heinous acts in the name of God.
他想再次做同樣的事
He wants to do the same thing again.
利用我潛入教會
Using me to infiltrate the Church.
魔鬼最大的勝利…
What greater victory for the devil...
就是奪得教皇驅魔人的靈魂
than to claim the soul of the pope's exorcist?
也許是 但現在我們知道它的名字了
Maybe. But we know his name now.
所以我們已有擊敗它和拯救那孩子
So we have what we need to beat it
所需的一切
and to save the child.
唯一能打敗我們的就是我們自己
The only thing that can defeat us is ourselves.
他會利用你的罪來對付你
He will use your sins against you.
我必須認罪
I need to make confession.
-向我？-你不是牧師嗎？
- To me? - You are a priest, are you not?
原諒我 神父 因為我犯了罪
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
倚靠耶和華
Trust in the Lord.
我要和你談談…
I want to talk to you...
關於我之前已認罪…
about things I have confessed before...
但仍然給我帶來負擔的事
but they still burden me.
在1942年…
In 1942...
戰爭期間 我加入了抵抗組織
during the war, I joined the Resistance.
我成為游擊隊員 並與法西斯分子作戰
I became a partisan and I fought against the fascists.
我很多戰友都死於德國人槍下
So many of my friends would die to German bullets.
為什麼是他們…
Why them...
而不是我？
and not me?
他們的屍體會在夢中跟我說話
Their dead bodies would talk to me in my dreams.
戰死沙場是英勇的
To die in a war is heroic.
在戰爭後存活…
To survive a war...
是複雜的
complex.
然後我開始體會…
And then I begin to see...
我的生命得以倖免
that my life had been spared.
我有責任賦予它生存的目的
It was my responsibility to give it purpose.
就我而言 這意味著侍奉上帝
And in my case, that meant to serve God.
多年來 我一直在努力接受馬太福音中所說的
In all of my years, I have tried to embrace what is said in Matthew.
「你為你們當中最少的人所做的
"What you do for the least among you,
就是為我做的 」
you do for me."
但是在重要時刻…
But when it mattered...
我失敗了
I failed.
我沒有幫助她 或相信她
I did not help her, I did not believe her.
我不聽她的話
I did not listen.
羅莎莉亞？
Rosaria?
羅莎莉亞
Rosaria.
晚上 魔鬼會和我上床
At night, the devil fucks me.
這惡魔長什麼樣子？
What does this devil look like?
像你
You.
她沒有被附身…
She was not possessed.
她是神經錯亂
She was mentally disturbed.
所以我讓別人處理她的案件
So I let someone else handle her case.
又一次…
Again...
是我的傲氣
my pride.
我是驅魔人
I was an exorcist.
精神錯亂的人不關我的事
The mentally disturbed, it's not my job.
現在你相信我嗎？
Do you believe me now?
但那一切就因為她…而改變了
But that all changed because of her.
聽說 在她死後
To hear after her death
那些性虐待的謠言 遮掩的行為
the rumors of the sexual abuse, the coverup
都在梵蒂岡城牆內
within the walls of the Vatican City.
那無辜的女孩
That innocent girl.
我在她需要我時沒有幫助她
I did not help her when she needed me.
她的靈魂…
Her soul
是我的負擔
is my burden.
這個惡魔 它知道這件事
And this demon, he knows that.
我所認識的你…
I know you...
作為上帝謙卑的人… 阿莫斯神父
as a humble man of God, Father Amorth.
是時候放下這個負擔了
It's time to lay down that burden.
原諒我 天父
Forgive me, Father.
我奉聖父
I absolve you of your sins
聖子和聖靈之名 赦免你的罪孽
in the name of the Father, of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit.
阿門
Amen.
我給你奇跡勳章
I give you the miraculous medal.
聖火保險
Holy fire insurance.
非常有能力
Very powerful.
要打敗地獄之王
To defeat the king of hell...
我們需要上帝的盔甲
we require the armor of God.
要打敗地獄之王
To defeat the king of hell...
我們需要上帝的盔甲
we require the armor of God.
記住 惡魔會利用你的感官來對付你
Remember, the demon will use your sins against you.
不要相信你看到或聽到的一切
Do not believe everything you see or hear.
我們有事要做
We have work to do.
我們必須救這孩子
We must save this child.
都告白罪了嗎？
All done confessing?
神父
Father.
他向你袒露他的靈魂了嗎 托馬斯？
Did he bare his soul to you, Tomas?
就像你的小妓女那樣露出她的乳房？
Like your little whore bared her breasts?
別理它
Ignore it.
為亨利祈禱
Pray for Henry.
再多的祈禱也救不了亨利
No amount of prayers can save Henry.
讓我進去 加布裏爾
Let me in, Gabriele.
你知道我要什麼
You know what I want.
我們在… 天上的父…
Our Father, who art in heaven...
-願禰的名受顯揚 -願禰的國降臨
- In heaven, hallowed be thy name. - ...hallowed be thy name.
願禰的旨意… -向你的…
Thy kingdom come, thy...
上帝懺悔有效嗎 加布？
Was there really any point confessing to your god, Gabe?
-求禰今天賞給我們日用的食糧… -你不該向她認罪嗎？
- Give us this day our... - Shouldn't you be confessing to her?
你…不存在
You are not there.
你只是存在我腦海裏
You are only in my mind.
因為你 我在地獄中被燒
I burn in hell because of you!
你不存在
You are not there.
你只是存在我腦海裏
You are only in my mind.
-神父 -和我們下地獄吧 加布
- Father. -  Join us in hell, Gabe.
讓我進去
Take me in.
你不要我嗎 托馬斯？
Don't you want me, Tomas?
叫我跪下來祈禱
Tell me to get on my knees and say my prayers.
跟我睡吧 托馬斯
Fuck me, Tomas.
騙子… -跟我睡吧 托馬斯
- Deceiver. - Fuck me, Tomas!
-騙子  -跟我睡吧 牧師
- Deceiver! - Fuck me, priest.
-天啊  -托馬斯 專心祈禱
- Oh, God. - Tomas, focus on the prayer!
阿斯蒙蒂斯
Asmodeus!
阿斯蒙蒂斯 格赫瑪之王 這是主的十字架
Asmodeus, king of Gehemma, this is the cross of the Lord!
釋放這個孩子 逃離上帝的光
Release this child and flee from the light of God!
降伏於上帝吧
See thee beneath God!
絕不 出去
Never. Get out.
-滾出我的家  -這是上帝的家
- Get out of my house. - This is the house of God!
沒有我兒子我不走
Not without my son!
你兒子死了
Your son is gone.
他的靈魂在地獄中燃燒腐爛
His soul burns and rots in hell.
-承認你的名字 阿斯蒙蒂斯 -絕不
- Admit to thy name, Asmodeus. - Never!
向全能的神屈膝
And bow to the power of God almighty.
-讓我進去 加布  -瑪利亞…
- Take me in, Gabe. -  Oh, Mary...
與你同在 天使之母… -你在婦女中是有福的…
- ...Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou... - And of the angels...
我是王
I am king.
你受我主宰
You're under my dominion.
我們謙卑地懇求你…
- We humbly beseech you...
-你從天主手中領受… -你將永遠…
- And here you will…
-權力和使命… -永遠留在地獄
remain damned forever!
現在和我們臨終時
...now and at the hour of our death.
去踏碎魔鬼頭顱
...to crush Satan's skull.
我是阿斯蒙蒂斯 地獄之王
I am Asmodeus, king of hell.
我命令你
And I command you!
我們懇求你派遣你的聖天使
We beseech thee to send thy holy angels,
在你的命令和權柄之下
that under thy command and by thy power,
追擊地獄的惡魔 處處擊打它們
they may pursue the evil spirits, encounter them on every side,
驅逐它們無恥的侵襲
resist their bold attacks,
再把它們打入地獄裏去
and drive them hence into the abyss of woe!
媽媽？
Mommy?
媽媽 救我
Mom, help me.
跟他說話 茱莉亞 跟他說話
Speak to him, Julia. Speak to him.
母愛永不言敗
A mother's love never fails.
亨利 亨利 我愛你
Henry. Henry, I love you.
跟他說話 -亨利 回到我身邊
- Call to him. - Henry, come back to me.
亨利 求你和我說話
Henry, please talk to me.
媽媽 它們在傷害我
Mommy, they're hurting me.
天啊
Oh, God.
亨利… 我們需要你的幫忙
Henry, we need your help.
你必須抵制
You must resist.
我不能
I can't.
你必須抵制
You must resist!
媽媽？
Mom?
亨利
Henry.
不在這裏
發生什麼事？
What's happening?
上帝不在這裏
天啊
Oh, my God.
糟了
Holy shit.
全能的上帝
Almighty God.
它附身在他們倆身上
It's in them both.
艾米
Amy.
-給我我想要的東西  -不
- Give me what I want! - No!
投降吧
Surrender yourself to me.
茱莉亞
Julia!
我告訴過你了
I told you, bitch.
你們都會死
You're all gonna die!
-艾米 求求你  -艾米走了
- Amy, please. - Amy's gone.
茱莉亞 抵制
Julia, resist!
不要失去信心
Don't lose faith!
把我的孩子還給我
Give me back my children!
你的孩子沒了
Your children are gone!
求求你
Please.
艾米 求求你
Amy, please.
我愛你
I love you.
你要的是我 放過那些孩子
It's me you want. Let the children go.
他們都因為你而受苦
They all suffer because of you.
說吧 小豬
Say the words, piggy.
成為你夢寐以求的殉道者
Be the martyr you dreamed of being.
做我的小豬
Be my piggy.
來抓我
Take me.
媽媽
Mom?
不 加布裏爾
No, Gabriele!
神父
Father.
媽媽？
Mommy?
你做了什麼？
What have you done?
從我手裏拿走十字架
- Take the cross from my hand. - Okay.
-好 -拿去
- Take it. - Okay.
天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
天啊 亨利 你回來了
Oh, my God. Henry, you came back to me.
-現在你安全了 -拿去
- You're safe now. - Take it!
帶他們離開這裏  去
Get them out of here. Go!
嘿
Hey. Hey.
茱莉亞 我們該走了
Julia, we have to go!
-摟著我 -求求你 走吧
- Put your arms around me. - Let's go.
Come on, run.
快 跑
艾米 快
Amy, come on.
你的靈魂是我的
Your soul is mine.
沙利文
Sullivan.
Sullivan!
我就知道你會犧牲自己來拯救那些孩子…
I knew you would sacrifice yourself to save those children,
現在你是我的
and now you are mine.
走 快點
Come on. Hurry.
那孩子 現在他安全了 離開這裏就是了
The boy, he's safe now. Just get away from here.
-走吧  -謝謝你 神父
- Go. - Thank you, Father.
我要我的豬 加布
I need my pig, Gabe.
你不能侵入我
You will not take me.
You will not take me!
你這個驕傲的傻瓜 修士也說了同樣的話
You prideful fool. The friar said the exact same thing.
原諒我 主啊
Forgive me, Lord.
還不行
Not yet!
我需要我的豬把我帶到梵蒂岡 加布
I need my pig to get me inside the Vatican, Gabe.
加布裏爾
Gabriele!
該死的我們倆…
Damn us both...
都下地獄
to hell.
加布裏爾
Gabriele!
你太遲了 托馬斯
You're too late, Tomas.
他死了 你的朋友 死了
He's gone, your friend. Gone.
那麼…
So...
走吧
run along.
我很榮幸
It would be my great pleasure
能摧毀你的靈魂 並剔除你的記憶
to excoriate your soul and eviscerate your memory.
加布裏爾 聽我說 抵制它
Gabriele, listen to me. Fight it.
它只是在你腦海裏
It is just in your head.
我們只能被自己打敗
We can only be defeated by ourselves.
他不在這裏
He is not here!
小豬在地獄的水槽裏撒潑
The little piggy is slopping at hell's trough,
那是他所屬的地方
where he belongs.
我知道你還在 加布裏爾 跟我一起祈禱
I know you're here, Gabriele. Pray with me.
上帝不在這裏
God is not here!
上帝一直在我們心裏
God is always in our hearts.
專心祈禱
Focus on the prayer.
「當有兩個人…
"Where two of you gather...
奉我的名聚會…那裏就有我 」
in my name, there am I."
求主憐憫
Lord, have mercy.
說吧 求主憐憫
Say it! Lord, have mercy!
上帝與你同在 加布裏爾 尋找它吧
God is with you, Gabriele. Find him!
了結它 托馬斯
Finish it, Tomas.
了結它
Finish it!
神啊 奉禰的名 拯救我
God, by your name, save me.
憑禰的大能為我伸冤
Judge me in thy strength.
神阿 求禰聽我的禱告
O God, hear my prayer.
留心聽我口中的言語
Listen to the words of my mouth.
神是我的幫助
Behold, God is my helper.
放棄吧 他是我的
Give up. He is mine.
我命令你以無瑕羔羊的名義
I adjure you in the name of the spotless lamb.
話語道成了肉身命令你
The word made flesh commands you.
阿斯蒙蒂斯
Asmodeus!
拿撒勒人耶穌命令你
Jesus of Nazareth commands you!
現在 我以祂的名義命令你
And now, I adjure you in his name!
主啊 聽我的禱告
Lord, heed my prayer!
-說 -不
- Say it! - No!
- 加布裏爾 -我們還沒來個了斷
- Gabriele. - We're not done yet.
你們會下地獄的 牧師們
You're coming to hell, priests.
我會帶你們倆去
I will take you both.
阿黛拉
Adella.
你們的罪必追上…
Your sins will seek...
必追上你們
Seek you out!
托馬斯 用勳章
Tomas, use the medal!
主啊 賜予我力量
Lord, grant me the power!
加布裏爾
Gabriele!
以聖母之名
Asmodeus. In the name of the Holy Mother.
降伏於上帝吧
See thee beneath God.
See thee beneath God!
托馬斯 祈禱最後的儀式
Tomas! Pray the final rites.
奉聖父…聖子 聖靈之名
In the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit...
降伏於上帝吧
see thee beneath God!
加布裏爾 你還好嗎？
Gabriele, are you okay?
還不錯
Not so bad.
-托馬斯 -什麼？
- Tomas. - What?
你看起來糟透了
You look like shit.
神祝福你 托馬斯
Bless you, Tomas.
你學會了拉丁語
You learned the Latin.
是的 它和西班牙語很相似
Yes, it's similar to the Spanish.
和西班牙語非常相似
Very similar to the Spanish.
聽著
Look.
你知道嗎 上帝…的作為… 是何等奧秘
You know, the God, he works in very mysterious ways.
為了你
For you.
是的 的確是
Yes, he does.
咕咕
Cuckoo.
是你嗎 加布裏爾？
Is that you, Gabriele?
是的 教皇陛下
Yes, Your Holiness.
我帶了埃斯基貝爾神父來見你
And I have brought Padre Esquibel to meet you.
你看起來很好 教皇陛下
You look well, Your Holiness.
謝謝你們 很高興見到你
Thanks to you both. I'm glad to see you.
這一次你讓我擔心了
You had me worried this time.
聽起來很危險
Sounded dangerous.
是的 還不錯
Yeah, not too bad.
有時你飛得離太陽有點太近了
Sometimes you fly a little too close to the sun.
我還沒被殺死
It has not killed me yet.
教會不會忘記你所做的一切
The Church will not forget what you have done.
你給了我們一個沉重的打擊
You struck a mighty blow for our side.
聖邁克爾會感到自豪
Saint Michael would be proud.
這就是上帝把你放在這裏的原因 加布裏爾
And this is why God put you here, Gabriele.
非常感謝 教皇陛下
Thank you very much, Your Holiness.
還有上帝選擇你是正確的 埃斯基貝爾神父
And God has made a good choice in you too, Father Esquibel.
謝謝你 教皇
Thank you, Holy Father.
會眾要求提供有關西班牙的完整報告
The congregation has requested a full report on Spain.
一個完整的報告
A full report.
讓沙利文大主教再告訴我 邪惡只存在於想像嗎？
So Cardinal Sullivan can tell me again that evil only exists in my imagination?
你還沒聽說？
You haven't heard?
沙利文大主教在關島休假
Cardinal Sullivan has taken a sabbatical in the Isle of Guam.
我要為…關島祈禱
I shall pray for Guam.
那麼誰…接替他呢？
And who has, uh, filled his shoes?
我找到了一個更值得信賴的人
I have found someone far more trustworthy.
他會好好照顧你
I will leave you in his good hands.
降伏於…上帝之下
See thee beneath God.
降伏於上帝之下
- See thee beneath God. - See thee beneath God.
歡迎來到最神聖的地方
Welcome to the holiest of holies.
十二個世紀的寶藏
Twelve centuries of treasures.
來自聖人和使徒的信件
Letters from saints and apostles.
智慧和虔誠的書籍
Books of wisdom and piety.
靈的啟示
Revelations of the spirit.
所有的經典基督教思想
The entire canon of Christian thought.
梵蒂岡從巴斯克斯家族手中買下修道院
The Vatican has purchased the abbey from the Vasquez family
並重新祝聖了土地
and reconsecrated the soil.
他們一家人安全搬回美國 小孩完全康復
The family has safely relocated back to the U.S.,
他們一家人安全地搬回美國 小孩完全康復
where the boy made a full recovery.
事實證明修士的日記很有用 儘管他深惡痛絕
The friar's diary is proving very useful, despite his abhorrence.
阿斯摩蒂爾斯被擊敗 但還有更多有待發現
Asmodeus has been defeated, but there are many more to be found.
很快我們就會找出地球上其他199個
Soon we will know all of the other 199 sites on earth
不歡迎上帝的地點
where God is not welcome.
加布裏爾 你願意接受這個任務嗎？
Gabriele, will you take on this task?
對於一個牧師來說 用一輩子來做也不夠
This would be more than a lifetime's work for one priest.
但兩個牧師…
But two priests...
你覺得呢 托馬斯？ 現在你能把它看作是一種召喚嗎？
What do you think, Tomas? Can you see this now as a calling?
我們必須按照上帝的旨意來侍奉上帝？
And that we must serve God the way he wants us to serve him?
我們開工吧
Let's go to work.
我們去地獄吧
Let's go to hell.
加布裏爾阿莫斯神父
(繼續為受苦的人服務 直到2016年在羅馬去世)
他同時也寫了很多書
那些書都很好
改編自「一位驅魔人的故事」
和「驅魔人：更多故事」 作者 FR 加布裏爾阿莫斯
加布裏爾阿莫斯神父 (1925-2016